Deployment and Implementation Success Factors
Welcome to this session on deployment planning.
Specifically, how do we deploy and implement Six Sigma.
To begin the session, I want to look at
and scrutinize some of the success factors.
That will help us indirectly understand how to better
implement and deploy. Specifically, how do we plan deployments?
Well, recall what we said in the past,
that in order to successfully deploy it,
we have to have clearly defined business related needs.
If those business needs are not clearly defined,
it's going to be very difficult to define good deployment plans.
Then we have to translate business and customer needs into metrics.
And that's the key here. Absolute key.
Is the ability to translate customer needs into metrics.
Third, we must be resolved to achieve true,
true world-class status. We’ve gotta have the will to do that.
Fourth, we need superordinate goals based on benchmarking.
In other words, we can't just say we're best in class.
We need to have quantitative goals based on benchmarking
and then set superordinate levels of change, of improvement.
Absolutely essential.
I want to focus on that word superordinate.
It’s a very keyword. Stretch goals.
Superordinate. Because we want people to re-examine the way in which the work get done,
not tweak the existing system. So, we set superordinate goals based on benchmarking.
Then we want and uncompromising roadmap for achieving breakthrough.
Now, why do I say uncompromising? We don't want to see
it watered down over time. So, it's got to be uncompromising.
Six. We want the assignment of our best people to the Six Sigma roles.
Absolute must. Define a career path to these Six Sigma roles.
A defined career path. Now, that I don't mean you’re going to be a career black belt.
What that means is you leave a job, come in to become a black belt,
and you go on into another job of higher responsibility.
So people that participate as a black belt want a defined career path,
once they have succeeded.
That's in line with the idea of meaningful rewards and recognition
for all the Six Sigma players.
We want vertically correlated performance metrics. Absolutely essential.
Our business metrics must be vertically correlated to the operations metrics
and to the process metrics.
We want variable pay linked to performance of those metrics. That's item number 10.
Linking pay is key to performance.
Then we want nonnegotiable performance targets for those projects.
Absolutely nonnegotiable targets for black belt projects.
We want documented project selection process. That’s another key to success.
You've gotta have a process that’s documented on how you're going to select
your application projects. Not just for black belts, but green belts and white belts as well.
We’ve also found that you gotta have systems to support, track, and report progress.
Without that, you don't know where you're going.
It’s like trying to steer the ship by looking at the wake of the boat.
So you gotta be able to have those systems, like radar, to help you track
and report your progress.
You gotta commit the economic resources. Without that, you're going nowhere.
Get rid of all the alphabet soup in your organization.
Get rid of the UFO, KGB, DDY, ABC programs,
and soft initiatives that are not linked.
See, to your focus. Get rid of those.
Have an intolerance to pilot programs and proof of principle projects.
And finally, self-sustain your training and education.
Last thing you want is a whole bunch of consultants in your organization,
you can't get rid of for sixteen years.
You’ve gotta be self-sustaining.
Create the master black belts and everything to self-sustain your initiative.
Finally, people love to hear success. Tell them.
Get out there and create a communications effort to communicate
your Six Sigma successes. That's absolutely essential.
So those are some of the critical lessons learned.
For me personally, after about 20 years and  quite a few deployments.
Probably on the order forty, fifty major corporations of deploying this stuff in.
Of what I’ve walked away with, an understanding of what constitutes success.
What I want to make sure that happens and does not happen.
So again summarizing. We gotta have defined needs; turn needs into metrics;
set true world-class goals,  superordinate goals;
have an uncompromising roadmap on how we are going to get there;
assign our best people; define career paths for what's going to happen to these players
after they go back to their jobs; have meaningful rewards for their success;
ensure that performance metrics are vertically correlated;
have your pay linked to those metrics;
have non-negotiable targets for projects;
systems to support the selection of projects;
a process to select those projects; commit the economic resources
to make Six Sigma happen; get rid of all your alphabet soup stuff;
have an intolerance to pilot programs and proof of principle;
have self-sustained training; and communicate your successes.
You do those things in a high-quality way
and you're going to be well on your way to having a good Six Sigma deployment.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.